# RILTON FRANZONE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



riltonfranzone.com



riltonfranzone@gmail.com

### **ABOUT ME**

Software Engineer with 4+ years' experience leading teams and playing key roles in projects that impacted hundreds of thousands of lives.

With a high sense of proactiveness and ownership, my expertise spans diverse domains, from sleek web and mobile apps, down to robust backend systems and infrastructure management.

## MAIN SKILLS

- Javascript
- Typescript
- Ruby on Rails
- Python
- React and React Native
- SSR (Next.js, Gatsby)
- Node JS (Express, Nest)
- SQL (Postgres, MySQL)
- NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis)
- Queueing systems
- GraphQL (Apollo, Prisma)
- Web extension development
- Data scraping (Selenium)
- AWS (EC2, RDS, SNS, Cognito, S3)
- CI/CD Pipelines
- Docker

Note: I firmly believe that these are just tools, and I'm always eager to learn new ones according to diverse needs.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **CATALYZEX**

SEP 2022 - PRESENT SAN FRANCISCO, CA (REMOTE)

Crafting tools to boost the productivity of over 180K AI/ML professionals and scholars.

- Enhanced the performance of critical APIs by up to 70% through the implementation of a queuing system for processing heavy tasks and query optimization
- Engineered robust data pipelines for crawling and indexing over 400k code implementations from academic papers
- Led key initiatives, including a close-to-zero downtime migration from MongoDB Atlas to PostgreSQL in AWS RDS, third-party integrations with large portals like arxiv.org, and payments/subscription management with Stripe
- Designed incremental adoption of Next.js from a legacy Ruby on Rails app, enabling much faster iteration on UX and SEO
- Introduced CI pipelines and e2e tests for key features across the web app and Chrome extension
- Established and maintained multiple infrastructure services on AWS

### THE DRIVERS COOPERATIVE

AUG 2021 - AUG 2022 NEW YORK, NY (REMOTE)

The engineer responsible for driving key initiatives on rideshare mobile applications used by thousands of drivers and passengers in NYC.

- Fully implemented a scheduled trip system used by +6K drivers
- Introduced a brand new onboarding flow, allowing drivers to easily submit their documents and start driving much more quickly
- Remodeled the driver's app authentication using AWS Cognito for Single Sign-on (SSO)
- Setup a push notification system using Firebase and an internal message queue
- Through feature flags, enabled the gradual delivery of new app functionalities for certain users
- Developed efficient Postgres SQL queries, views, and procedures integrated with Hasura, enabling seamless generation of GraphQL APIs
- Created reusable and testable UI components utilizing Storybook, optimizing the development process and long-term maintenance of the applications

# WORK EXPERIENCE (COTINUATION)

#### **ARVOLUTION**

MAR 2021 - SEP 2021 MEXICO (REMOTE)

Arvolution automates and digitalizes the processes of warehouses. During my period there. I was one of the engineering leaders in our partnership with Soriana, the largest retail company in Mexico.

- Led a team of 4 engineers in the design and implementation of a warehouse management system used by +90K employees
- Improved the workflow of engineers by establishing best practices and guidelines for state management in the mobile application written in React Native with Redux and Apollo Cache
- Designed tens of RESTful APIs and orchestrated their development, constantly orienting other engineers and reviewing PRs
- Created high-quality and testable UI components used by many teams in various applications

#### LETSLUNCH

APR 2020 - FEB 2022 SAN FRANCISCO, CA (REMOTE, PART-TIME)

LetsLunch was a professional networking startup focused on connecting entrepreneurs to have lunch. As a part-time software engineer, I contributed to the following areas:

- Participated in the development of a lunch-matching feature that scheduled over 100K lunches in 6 different countries
- Designed and led the system migration from PHP to Node.js and Next.js, improving page load times and various SEO metrics

### **MESHA TECHNOLOGY**

AUG 2020 - MAY 2021 BRAZIL (REMOTE)

Mesha is a famous software house based in Brazil. During my time at the company, I was responsible development of both internal and external systems:

- Led a project partnership with one of the largest accounting companies of Rio de Janeiro
- Created top-notch interfaces with React, Ant Design, and SASS
- Built mobile applications with React Native
- · Helped and oriented more junior engineers in their onboarding process

### **CODEGEM**

MAY 2020 - SEP 2020 TORONTO, ON (REMOTE)

As a volunteer, I contributed to the company in the following areas:

- Improved all SEO metrics by introducing best practices and SSG with Gatsby
- Implemented row-level security policies in PostgreSQL, and documented the whole process for other engineers
- Played a key role in the development of the MVP, building important features from the backend to the frontend

### **EDUCATION**

BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE UNIVERSITY OF LONDON

FULL-STACK CODING BOOTCAMP ROCKETSEAT